Muhammad Zaryab Rafique

Phone number: (+92) 3347860477 Email address: muhammadzaryabrafique@gmail.com

WhatsApp Messenger: +923347860477

in LinkedIn: mzaryabrafique

GitHub: https://github.com/rust-master

• Home: Lahore (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

I am Zaryab, a self-motivated and enthusiastic individual with experience in blockchain development and software engineering. I specialize in Solidity, JavaScript, Rust, and dApps development using Stellar, Solana, and EVM chains, as well as core blockchain development with Substrate, Cosmos, and Golang. I have a proven track record of creating applications for both web3 and web2 on mobile and web platforms. My skills in blockchain, software engineering, and web3 technologies enable me to design, develop, and deploy digital solutions that meet the needs of modern businesses and individuals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Engineer

InvoZone [14/03/2022 - Current]

City: Lahore | Country: Pakistan

NFT Marketplace

- NFT Marketplace is built on the Ethereum blockchain. I worked in a team of three engineers, my role was to design the solution of the system and to write the web3 integration for smart contracts using web3.js.
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/rust-master/nft-marketplace

Crypto Funding dApp

• Developed web3 integration by implementing support for 12+ wallets using the WalletConnect library and MultiverseX wallet integration.

Substrate(Rust) based NPOS EVM Blockchain

- Build the Substrate-based Nominated POS blockchain and EVM & Ethereum compatible, deployed blockchain with 3 validators. My role was to write the EVM, Ethereum, and Staking pallets integration in Rust for the node.
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/rust-master/substrate-frontier-evm

Cosmos(Golang) Interchange Rollup

- My role was to write the interchange module order book and IBC integration, Rollkit setup, and deploy on the Celestia.
- Project URL: https://github.com/rust-master/interchange

Mobile App Developer

Sruplex [15/02/2021 - 15/02/2022]

City: Remote

Rukuh - Prayer Times

• My role is to develop a Prayer Time App in Android(Kotlin) using Jetpack Compose, Implemented the calculation of prayer time by location, and dynamic theme changes with prayer time. Firebase crashlytics integration.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science in Computer Sciences

COMSATS University Islamabad (CUI) [06/02/2018 - 06/03/2022]

Country: Pakistan

SKILLS

Blockchain Stack

Ethereum / Solidity / Stellar / Solana / Substrate / Cosmos / Soroban / EVM Chains / Smart Contracts / dApps / Web3 Integration / GOLang / Hardhat / Python / Raydium / ERCs (20 - 721 - 1155 ...) / NFT MarketPlace / DeFi (Decentralised Finance) / SPL Token / Tel egram Bots

Web Stack

|avascript(Nodeis, Express|s) / React |S / Mocha Tests / MongoDB / C# / ASP.Net MVC / Entity Framework / |ava / SQL

Rust Stack

Rust / Tokio / Meta Programming / Rust Tests / actix / rocket / Microservices / tonic - gRPC / PostgreSQL / Docker / Git

PROJECTS

Raydium Swap

allows users to swap tokens on the Raydium AMM platform built on the Solana blockchain using TypeScript. My role was to design the solution for swap and write typescript code for swap tokens on Raydium AMM. GitHub Repo: https://github.com/rust-master/raydium-swap-ts

Pricypto Telegram Bot

built in Golang that sends price alert messages to the channel every 2 minutes. GitHub Repo: https://github.com/rust-master/pricypto-telegram-bot

Crowdfunding Soroban Contract

built the crowdfunding project on the Stellar Blockchain, users can create the campaigns, donors can donate to the campaigns, and donation payment is split into three different accounts. My role was to write the contract in Rust using Soroban SDK, deploy on Mainnet, and write the web3 integration.

CERTIFICATES/MOOC

CERTIFICATES

- Back End Development and APIs (freecodecamp)
- Certified Blockchain Practitioner (CBP) (The SecOps Group)
- Decentralized Applications (Coursera)
- Blockchain Foundation Developer (IBM)
- Blockchain Essentials (IBM)
- Intermediate Python for Data Science (DataCamp)
- Blockchain Specialization (Coursera)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

English Arabic

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C1 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication, Teamwork, Leadership, Listening

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Football Playing, Book Reading, Workout